Paulo Leonardo Benatto

Brighton, UK benatto@gmail.com Phone: +44 07405110040 Post Code: SW16 2BU

Summary

Bachelor in computer science having expertise in software development, good professional relationship and focused at work. With more than 6 years of professional experience in software development using basically, C language and Linux platform. I am now looking for new challenges and opportunities that allow me to learn new technologies and work with new people. I have interest in software development (C/C++, Python, Java, Lua, ShellScript and Go) and Linux Operating System administration.

Open Source developer attending in projects like: libmalelf, malelf and libpenetra. All projects were developed in C language on Linux platform in order to analyze Linux and Windows binaries files.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2007.

Experience

Brandwatch

Jul 2014 - Present

Linux Systems Administrator

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, JS, Raspberry PI, Bareos, Ansible, Git;

The first project that I attended was to integrate Asterisk (log calls) and SalesForce. This small project was developed using Python, Flask framework, Html and JS.

I also developed a web application to change user's password (LDAP). This project envolves two parts. The first is responsible to verify and notify (by email) users to change their password each 6 months. The second is a web interface for authentication and changing the password. Again using Python and Flask.

- I've created a backup solution using Bareos/Bacula and all solution is deployed using ansible.
- \bullet Developed a solution in Python/Flask to migrate company emails (Exim) to GMail.
- Sometimes I work with Nagios, supporting and developing plugins in python.

In my spare time I like to study about programming languages such as Python, JavaScript, $\mathrm{C/C}++.$

DBA Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Raspberry PI and C;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop a system to analyse vehicle traffic on Brazilian highways. Basically my task was read traffic log files with all car's information (speed, length, time) and create a structure on memory to store and report human readable information. This project was developed using C language, Debian GNU/Linux OS, GLib and Valgrind (dynamic analyse tool). In parallel I attended of a project to develop a parking meter system, using python language and Raspberry PI. My main task was do inter-process communication using DBus.

 $\mathrm{SEC}+$ Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Django Framework, JavaScript and C;

Back-end development of web system for intelligent monitoring and management of natural disasters using Python and the Django framework. Front-end with Javascript (JQuery, Bootstrap, Google Maps API), JSON, HTML5, CSS. Modeling and use of object-relational database and geographic objects with PostgreSQL/PostGIS.

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Java, ShellScript;

Member of the team responsible to design and develop the roadmap features of a product called Guardião used to interecept calls and internet trafic of people whose are being investigated by the police. Specifically allocated on the design and development of a module which main goal is to intercept the actions done on Facebook, WhatsApp and Hotmail of a target, using the gathered data to cross reference with another possible targets.

Main activities: C Development, Scripting, Linux administration, Network Packet Analysis (Wireshark), debugging and testing software, Agile environment.

Digitro Technology - STE

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, VoIP, C/C++, shellscript, protocols: UDP, TCP, SIP;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop VoIP products. I attend in two big project:

- * In a team we developed a softphone, is a software program for making telephone calls over the Internet using a general purpose computer, rather than using dedicated hardware. The softphone runs in Windows platform and was developed using C Language, VisualStudio and sofia-sip library.
- * A VoIP phone that uses Voice over IP technologies for placing and transmitting telephone calls over an IP network. My main task in this project was cross-compiling the Enlightenment Foundation Libraries to develop the touch screen interface.

Other activities involves: Linux administration, C development, Python and Shell scripting, Network Packet analysis, debugging, profiling, code analysis, /etc.

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

Networkings: TCP/IP protocol suite;

Progamming Languages: C/C++, Pascal, Python, JavaScript, plus some experience with Lua and Java;

Virtualization: VirtualBox, VMWare, plus some experience with Xen;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Open Source Projects

- libpenetra: The libpenetra was created with the goal of studying the windows binary format known as Portable Executable (PE). With libpenetra you can access all information about PE binaries. (https://github.com/patito/libpenetra)
- **libmalelf**: The libmalelf is an evil library that SHOULD be used for good! It was developed with the intent to assist in the process of infecting binaries and provide a safe way to analyze malwares. (https://github.com/SecPlus/libmalelf)
- malelf: Malelf is a tool that uses librallelf to dissect and infect ELF binaries. (https://github.com/SecPlus/malelf)

More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/benatto
- **Github**: https://github.com/patito